<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>day3 | Science Accelerator</title>
    <link>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/tag/day3/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/tag/day3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>day3</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 10:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>day3</title>
      <link>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/tag/day3/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universes are Big Data: from geometry, to physics, to ML</title>
      <link>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/yanghuihe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/yanghuihe/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JBH9Qk96WN8&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We briefly overview how historically string theory led theoretical physics first to algebraic/differential geometry, and then to computational geometry, and now to data science. Using the Calabi-Yau landscape - accumulated by the collaboration of physicists, mathematicians and computer scientists over the last 4 decades - as a starting-point and concrete playground, we then launch to review our recent program in machine-learning mathematical structures and address the tantalizing question of how AI helps doing mathematics, ranging from geometry, to representation theory, to combinatorics, to number theory.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Triangle of Influence: Bringing Together Physics, Pure Mathematics, and Computer Science</title>
      <link>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/jimhalverson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/jimhalverson/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/RLkADPZhIck&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recent advances in machine learning have begun creating new bridges to physics and mathematics that have traditionally existed between the latter two. Given this progress, I will speculate about where we are and where things might be headed, including through the recently launched NSF AI Institute for Artificial Intelligence and Fundamental Interactions. Specifically, I’ll survey well-known machine learning results in supervised learning, reinforcement learning, and generative models, and explain cases where these techniques are already impacting physics and math. In more detail, I will explain some remarkable similarities between neural networks and quantum field theory that might point towards a theoretical understanding of deep learning, and also how an AI agent’s ability to unknot headphones might provide useful in cracking a foundational problem in topology.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baryons from Mesons: A Machine Learning Perspective</title>
      <link>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/challengermishra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/challengermishra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quantum chromodynamics (QCD) is the theory of the strong interaction. The fundamental particles of QCD, quarks and gluons, carry colour charge and form colourless bound states at low energies. The hadronic bound states of primary interest to us are the mesons and the baryons. From knowledge of the meson spectrum, we use neural networks and Gaussian processes to predict the masses of baryons with 90.3% and 96.6% accuracy, respectively. These results compare favourably to the constituent quark model. We as well predict the masses of pentaquarks and other exotic hadrons.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning as a Discovery Tool</title>
      <link>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/vishnujejjala/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/vishnujejjala/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/D7lF4BDRyBk&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we motivate string theory as a candidate theory of quantum gravity. The topology and geometry of the extra dimensions predicted by string theory determine aspects of the physics that we see every day. We use machine learning as a tool to probe this physics. We also use machine learning to explore the structure of the simplest quantum field theory. We conclude by giving prospects for the future of machine learning in theoretical physics and mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
