<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>day2 | Science Accelerator</title>
    <link>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/tag/day2/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/tag/day2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>day2</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 10:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>day2</title>
      <link>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/tag/day2/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical models for insightful machine learning</title>
      <link>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/markuskaiser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/markuskaiser/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Machine learning is a powerful tool to find explanations for data, but not all explanations are created equal. This talk will explore why collaboration with domain experts is critical for the successful application of machine learning in the industrial and scientific domains. We will focus on the expert-driven formulation and evaluation of hierarchical models and show how to specify what should be learned from data and how to apply the scientific principle to gain new and semantic insights.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Optimisation: Sequential Decision Making Under Uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/alessandratosi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/alessandratosi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Optimisation techniques are widely used to solve problems across any domain. In this talk we will focus on global optimisation of black-box functions using Bayesian optimisation, an iterative optimisation technique. We will explore how Bayesian optimisation can be used beyond the popular application of fine tuning the parameters of complex machine learning models and data science pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regression, Causality, Statistical Paradoxes and other Fairy Tales</title>
      <link>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/javiergonzales/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/javiergonzales/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Regression models can be useful in various ways. In this talk we will focus on how we can use them to compute causal effects, so we can augment our toolkit when reasoning about how the world around us works. We will review some basic concepts of causal reasoning and revisit some common statistical misconceptions that can easily avoided with proper causal thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inverse Problems in Biology, Deconvolution of Mixed Signals in Spatial Transcriptomics Data, and How to Use Matrix Factorization for Nearly Everything</title>
      <link>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/aleksandrinagoeva/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/aleksandrinagoeva/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Inverse problems arise when we want to use data to extract an insight into the inner workings of a system. Such problems are often ill-posed, meaning that there are multiple explanations compatible with the observations and it is therefore necessary to constrain the problem to arrive at a concrete solution. High-throughput high-resolution genome-wide spatial transcriptomics data is a recent breakthrough technology presenting great promise for gaining insights into cellular interactions and tissue-level systems biology. Extracting biologically useful knowledge from this new data modality comes with a novel set of computational challenges. One such challenge is figuring out how much different cell types have contributed to each spatial point measured from the tissue. We will go step-by-step over a simple, intuitive and interpretable solution (manifested by a matrix factorization) that utilizes expert-annotated reference data of cell types to constrain this ill-posed inverse problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
