<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>winterschool2021 | Science Accelerator</title>
    <link>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/tag/winterschool2021/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/tag/winterschool2021/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>winterschool2021</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 10:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>winterschool2021</title>
      <link>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/tag/winterschool2021/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI for scientific discovery: an introduction to Accelerate Science</title>
      <link>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/jessica/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/jessica/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Machine learning has the potential to become an engine for scientific discovery across disciplines – from predicting the impact of climate change, to using genetic data to create new healthcare treatments, and from finding new astronomical phenomena to identifying new materials here on Earth. Achieving this potential requires interdisciplinary collaborations that combine scientific insights with expertise in machine learning methods, creating machine learning systems that can be applied to ‘real-world’ problems. The Accelerate Programme for Scientific Discovery is a new initiative from Cambridge University’s Department of Computer Science and Technology, which will support researchers across the University to use machine learning to advance their research. This talk will introduce the thinking behind the Programme and its work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Machine Intelligence?</title>
      <link>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/neil/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/neil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With breakthroughs in understanding images, translating language, transcribing speech artificial intelligence promises to revolutionise the technological landscape. Machine learning algorithms are able to convert unstructured data into actionable knowledge. With the increasing impact of these technologies, society’s interest is also growing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word intelligence conjures notions of human-like capabilities. But are we really on the cusp of creating machines that match us? We associate intelligence with knowledge, but in this talk I will argue that the true marvel of our intelligence is the way it deals with ignorance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the large strides forward we have made, I will argue that we have a long way to go to deliver on the promise of artificial intelligence. And it is a journey that our societies need to take together, not just as computer scientists, but together by rediscovering the interdisciplinary spirit that is required to achieve real scientific progress.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Uncertainty in Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/andreasdamianou/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/andreasdamianou/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning and the Scientific Principle</title>
      <link>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/che/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/che/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Machine learning is the science of combining knowledge with data through computation. In this talk we will try to make these concepts mathematically stringent. We will first discuss how we can formulate our knowledge mathematically by building models. Importantly differently from logic machine learning is concerned with knowledge that is uncertain often referred to as beliefs. We will show how we can use probabilities as a mean to quantify our beliefs. In the second part of the talk we will see how we can combine our beliefs with observations and recover an updated belief. We will discuss the interplay between data and beliefs this will become important when choosing which machine learning method to use for different scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical models for insightful machine learning</title>
      <link>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/markuskaiser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/markuskaiser/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Machine learning is a powerful tool to find explanations for data, but not all explanations are created equal. This talk will explore why collaboration with domain experts is critical for the successful application of machine learning in the industrial and scientific domains. We will focus on the expert-driven formulation and evaluation of hierarchical models and show how to specify what should be learned from data and how to apply the scientific principle to gain new and semantic insights.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Optimisation: Sequential Decision Making Under Uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/alessandratosi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/alessandratosi/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regression, Causality, Statistical Paradoxes and other Fairy Tales</title>
      <link>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/javiergonzales/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/javiergonzales/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Regression models can be useful in various ways. In this talk we will focus on how we can use them to compute causal effects, so we can augment our toolkit when reasoning about how the world around us works. We will review some basic concepts of causal reasoning and revisit some common statistical misconceptions that can easily avoided with proper causal thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inverse Problems in Biology, Deconvolution of Mixed Signals in Spatial Transcriptomics Data, and How to Use Matrix Factorization for Nearly Everything</title>
      <link>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/aleksandrinagoeva/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/aleksandrinagoeva/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Inverse problems arise when we want to use data to extract an insight into the inner workings of a system. Such problems are often ill-posed, meaning that there are multiple explanations compatible with the observations and it is therefore necessary to constrain the problem to arrive at a concrete solution. High-throughput high-resolution genome-wide spatial transcriptomics data is a recent breakthrough technology presenting great promise for gaining insights into cellular interactions and tissue-level systems biology. Extracting biologically useful knowledge from this new data modality comes with a novel set of computational challenges. One such challenge is figuring out how much different cell types have contributed to each spatial point measured from the tissue. We will go step-by-step over a simple, intuitive and interpretable solution (manifested by a matrix factorization) that utilizes expert-annotated reference data of cell types to constrain this ill-posed inverse problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universes are Big Data: from geometry, to physics, to ML</title>
      <link>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/yanghuihe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/yanghuihe/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baryons from Mesons: A Machine Learning Perspective</title>
      <link>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/challengermishra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/challengermishra/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Networks and Quantum Field Theory</title>
      <link>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/jimhalverson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/jimhalverson/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning as a Discovery Tool</title>
      <link>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/vishnujejjala/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mlatcl.github.io/mlaccelerate/talk/vishnujejjala/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
